Day we're talking about agency sales.
This is a very, very big, very important topic.
I've given this presentation,
this is gonna be the third time, over five years.
This is the most updated version of
what I'm doing right now at our agency.
We're gonna go through this in a number of days.
It's all gonna be broken down
through this sales sub-process here.
So part one of the sales sub-process is the discovery call.
So I like to have an initial call touch point
with the client prospect, I should say,
before we get a proposal.
We'll go into why that is.
But it's mainly for qualification, not wasting time.
Just making sure that we're both on the same page
about what's about to go down.
Because the last thing that we want to do is spend a lot
of time or effort on a proposal for somebody
that's completely unqualified.
I never ever, ever,
ever send a proposal without having at least one
phone call with somebody.
I'm actually doing some white label work
through a another agency
and they keep on asking for proposals to send out.
And I'm like, absolutely not.
'cause when you do that, they look at it
and even if it's the best proposal in the world,
they're gonna s they're gonna self associate
with the pricing in there, with the deliverables in there.
You need to be able to walk them through that, right?
You never want to just send somebody blind pricing
or proposal without context in a conversation.
It's really, really, really,
really important that we do that.
So next up is gonna be the analysis plus proposal.
This is key. I talk about this a lot
and I will, in a large majority of
what we're gonna do in this bootcamp is going
through the analysis process.
This is a consultative process.
This is not just trying
to hard sell people and hard closed people.
The analysis is really important.
We're gonna talk about that in great detail.
Then I'll send them a scope of work.
We don't do contracts,
but if you do long-term contracts, 12 months, this is
where you want to get 'em to sign, right?
The proposal, you could add a signature in there too.
But I like to do this in two separate documents.
This is, hey, these are the areas
of weakness and opportunity.
Here's the proposed work to fix that.
And then that's all buttoned up in a single, much easier
to read Word document, scope of work,
deliverables, timeline.
And if you want to get 'em to sign there,
that's a good place to get 'em to sign.
This would be like the agreement,
contract, whatever it is that you wanna call it.
I call it a scope of work
because we don't make them sign it.
This is just to get on the same page about what's about
to go down when we start working for 'em.
Then the close process too.
So close process is different than other sales types, right?
I was talking to this kid who does solar sales,
and that is a very different sales process
and close process to get people over the finish line.
We're gonna talk about follow ups, how to follow up,
do you call people, do you harass people?
We're gonna talk about all that
because we get a lot of questions there.
And I think it's, it's, it's understandably so
because it's a very sensitive, difficult process
to understand how to maneuver without being too aggressive
and scaring people away, but also putting enough pressure on
them to actually get them over the finish line.
And then we're gonna go into a lot of bonus stuff here.
We're gonna do a ton of q and a,
but we're gonna talk about potentially managing a sales
department with multiple reps, CRM, set up, management,
update, internal communication, all that type of stuff.
We're gonna go into detail on that.
So, so, uh, this is important information.
I wanna make sure that we communicate this
because, you know, you as leaders, founders,
you're always gonna have your hand in the sales pot in one
way, shape, or form or another.
So, speaking of which, let's talk
about who owns this process.
There are multiple ways to skin this cat, if you will,
in terms of who owns it, who does it.
Most of us, and I say us
'cause I'm included in this, is like a founder
led sales process, right?
You are the managing partner, you're the founder,
you're an executive, you're a leader in the company.
You could be doing all the sales,
and I'm gonna talk a lot about how I handle this
because I do 100% of the sales for our agency,
and it sounds crazy at the size that we are,
but I'll break down exactly how I do that.
You know, I've waffled back
and forth, like I said, between doing it myself
and hiring sales reps.
I've had three sales reps over the past, you know,
decade doing this, and I've really struggled,
and this is me being honest with you, all right?
Like, I've really struggled to find somebody
who can handle the load because it is equal parts marketing.
SEO strategist and specialist consultative, somebody
who can speak to the problems in detail,
and then somebody who also possesses the communication
skills, the, the authority, if you will,
to actually move deals over the finish line.
Those are two very different things.
No shade to SEOs,
but SEOs a lot of times are not the best communicators.
A little bit more technical, skilled than creative
or communication skilled.
And a lot of true sales reps are very heavy on the Wolf
of Wall Street stuff, heavy closing,
and they don't know how to do consultations.
And I'm going through this now through this agency that's,
that's white labeling our, our services.
We're talking, this is probably like a 50
to a hundred million dollars agency, huge agency.
They do a lot of at-home advertising for lawyers
and, and just big companies.
They brought us on to just fulfill SEO
because they don't do it,
and they just prefer to subcontract that.
And they've got like 10, you know,
account executive sales reps,
and they're all older people too, right?
They go to events and they,
they bring in these big company leads,
but man, they don't really know too much on the technical
or the, the marketing skill side of things.
And even in the stuff that they're talking about too, right?
They're, they're mainly relationship brokers
and, you know, it's, it's, it's one vision
that company's way bigger than we are.
But the close rate, when I come in
and I'm able to have conversations
with people about the problems that they've had
with agencies in the past, the mismanaged expectations, why
that happens, what's actually going on in their industry
from a marketing and advertising point of view,
what's working, all these different things.
It creates a different layer of trust.
And uh, our close rate for ourselves is very, very, very,
very good because of the ability
to consult throughout the process
and make them feel, you know,
like you're the first touchpoint before your team gets in.
It's a, it's a great way
to bring people in and to close them.
So the other option that you have,
like I said, is to hire a sales rep.
You know, if you yourself are just not good at sales at all,
or you don't feel comfortable,
or frankly it's just too much work
because it's a lot of work, then there's obviously the
option to hire a sales rep.
You can put 'em through this training,
but just know that what I'm gonna teach you here is very,
very consultative.
Like you have to know SEO inside
and out to be able to sell the
way that I'm gonna teach you to sell.
Someone has to. So that's why it's so important,
because I want to, I don't want
to teach you some shotgun approach and the,
because the reason is too, guys, is that like leads
for SEO are not what they used to be.
It's just, it's, it doesn't reach as large of the market.
It's not for every business anymore.
Not everyone's a good fit.
So the opportunities that you do have, you have to treat
with extreme care and attention
and to pawn it off to a sales rep who
is just jockeying proposals
and hammering the phone to close them,
it's not gonna have the highest success rate for you.
So, you know, back in the day when you could cold call
people and get businesses interested, not saying
that you can't, but it's just a different approach, right?
So I'm gonna teach you very high touch,
very high value sales that you can train a sales rep with.
But you know, the way that I do it
and the way that I've been able to scale this is,
let me just go back to the previous slide here, right?
So I handle the discover call.
This is a 30 minute call, crush it, right?
Then I have an SEO specialist
who I hired from another agency.
Her name is Annette. Her full-time role is
to just work on analysis proposals, managing the CRM,
helping out with email communication.
She'll do, she'll handle SEO work
overflow if our pipeline is slow.
But this analysis takes, you know, two to three hours
to put together and it's a template that I'm gonna give you.
So it still takes a good amount of time,
but that this is off my plate, right?
Then I do the call with them. That's an hour call.
So hour and a half so far.
She'll put together the scope of work.
Sometimes we'll do a call here, it's about a 30 minute call.
So we're talking about two hours
of my time all on a call, right?
Over the course of this could be two weeks,
two months, six months.
It's not a ton of time invested.
But where the work really starts
to pile up is doing the analysis scope of work,
the CRM management, the email faults, all
that stuff can really start to add up.
So I've been able to offload the very busy work part
of this, which is putting together the documentation.
And that's where a lot of agencies struggle when I do audits
and consultations with agencies, you know, looking at sales
and why deals aren't closing.
There's always a bottleneck in sales.
You know, the agency that bought mine eight years ago,
we had a sales rep and none
of the founders got involved in sales is the,
we would do like, you know, like pop in to talk to clients
and be like, oh, it is an
executive whatever, blah, blah blah.
But we had two sales reps
and like they were responsible to do everything,
all the calls, all the proposals,
and like it would take like a week
or two to get this stuff out
and you gotta strike when the iron's hot.
We're able to turn around analysis
and proposals within 24 hours, sometimes 24 to 48 hours.
What I tell prospects, so they come in,
they have a great discovery call, they're excited,
we're able to get an analysis
in front of them that's amazing.
Within two days in a full scope
of work, within a week, right?
So very, very fast turnaround on this stuff.
Give 'em everything they need to make a decision
and then from there we can build more rapport as needed.
So that is how I run a,
basically a founder led sales program.
And it's what I would recommend for you too, right?
But it's all about hiring support to help you out
because you cannot do it all
because you also have other stuff
going on too inside the company.
I don't deal with client work
Per se, but there's times when I'll get involved,
jump on calls here and there were clients, you know,
I do our marketing, I also run the blueprint training.
I'm a very busy guy. So for me to be able
to do this, you can do it too.
But the key is, is finding that person
and that person you can also then train
to potentially take over calls as well.
But you gotta train them on how
to do the analysis portion of this.
That make sense? Alright,
so let's talk about what tools we need.
One, you're gonna need A-C-R-M-I love ActiveCampaign.
It's what I use. It's
what I'm gonna be showing you throughout this program.
Streak is in any email CRM that you can use.
There's a free version of also a paid version of it.
I do recommend that if you don't want to use, if you have,
if you're only doing like less than four deals a month
or less than four, like, you know,
pipelines per month streak is okay.
But active campaign is really good
because it also has all your contacts.
They're on your email list. I love it.
It's very easy to use. But you know,
you can use HubSpot, you can use pipe drive.
There's other platforms you can use too.
But I'm gonna be showing you how I use active campaign.
So video call, obviously Zoom, meet,
whatever you're comfortable with, you're gonna need some
sort of video call software.
They should always be done there.
And if you have sales reps too,
they should have their own account.
You don't wanna be sharing accounts on Zoom, it's,
it just becomes a backup in a a bot.
Another unnecessary bottleneck booking.
I like Calendly, but like HubSpot, a lot
of these platforms have their own booking link.
It just makes booking meetings a lot faster and easier.
I'm going through this now with this other agency like, Hey,
can you send me four times that
you're available over the next week?
I'm like, dog. Like, come on man. Like check my calendar.
By the time that they pick a time this happened to me today,
that time slot's already booked.
So I'm just like, just check a time that works for you.
TR projection tool is a tool that we own internally.
It helps us with forecasting for SEO.
It's a great tool that we'd like to put into our analysis.
Just helps to answer the question of
what can I expect from results
and when is it a hundred percent accurate?
Absolutely not. But is it better than nothing? Absolutely.
And then you're gonna need an SEO tool, either SEMrush
or Arus, whichever you're comfortable with.
I believe we used Ahrefs, but they're interchangeable.
Whatever y'all are comfortable with, use that.
So that's everything that you're gonna need from a tools
point of view to run this.
And now I wanna talk about core principles of agency sales.
Again, I, I love to use this like the Wolf of Wall Street,
the Wolf of Wall Street imagery here.
Because a lot of us, when we think about sales,
we think about hard closing, we think about tonality.
I dunno if you've ever taken his jor,
this is Leo DiCaprio obviously,
but Jordan Belfort had a sales training
called the Straight Line Program.
Amazing sales training. I went through it 10 years ago.
It's all about like, and all that different stuff.
And it kind of applies here,
but it doesn't really apply here, right?
You know, this is not a Wolf of Wall Street approach.
You are an advisor, you're a consultant,
you are a subject matter expert before you're a salesperson.
That's what you are and
that's what's gonna help you out the most.
Because the hardest part about selling in this industry is
that people are jaded, right?
They've been burned by agencies before.
They've heard that, you know,
they're gonna get results and they don't.
They've been over promise and under delivered.
So the best way to beat that back,
especially if you don't have a huge track record in case
studies and client results, is to get them to trust you.
You get them to trust you through really good communication
and demonstration of your knowledge on the problem
and the task at hand.
So another thing is
that some deals will close on one call, some will take a year.
This happens all the time. Uh, that's why it's good
to have an email list and always maintain good communication
and relationships with people.
I know it can be tempting sometimes if people ghost on you
to like send them an FU email.
But the fact is, is that it's not about you.
It's about them. They have their own timelines.
Agency deals can take a long time
because they have budgets to take, take into account.
They have other agencies that maybe they're engaged with.
They have time of the year constraints.
They have, well we're building new
websites, so we wanna wait.
There's so many constraints on, it's not like a,
it's not like buying a, I don't know, a bag of coffee
where you just, you need coffee so you buy it, right?
It can, there's a lot of factors that go into it.
So you never wanna burn a, a relationship with somebody
because they might be going through the process,
they're just not ready to buy now.
But I get emails all the time.
I got two this week from people
that are like, we're ready to go.
Like let's do it. Let's pull the trigger.
That happens at least once a month.
We get somebody who comes back that ghosted.
Sometimes it's like two years. It's pretty crazy.
But that's why I like active campaign
and why creating content is so important.
'cause I'm always creating content.
I'm always pushing it out.
They'll get the emails, we'll stay top of mind
and then when they're ready, they just reply to the emails
and they're like, Hey, like we're ready to get this going.
So always keep a good relationship. Communication.
So this is important too.
You're not selling services, you're selling results.
And the faster the better. Now I know we're selling SEO
here, that's mainly what we're talking about.
But this is why you've seen us talk a lot about blended
search, paid search LSAs, adding in Facebook ads.
But how this specifically applies to SEO is saying, okay,
if we're selling SEO, that's what we sell.
That's what the prospect is here for.
How do we make this about outcomes
and not just about deliverables on a spreadsheet, right?
So when we talk about how to do that, right,
how do we make this about outcomes when this is
like a task-based service.
It's about forecasting,
it's about showing any results that you have.
It is about giving them an idea of what to expect, right?
It's not just like a lot
of SEOs come in and they're like, here's what you're getting.
And it's like keyword research, 10 20 track track keywords.
Like that's great. But that goes into the scope of work
that doesn't go into the analysis
and the proposal, the end analysis
and the proposal is about identifying problems
and areas of opportunity.
So like, hey, your website's slow. We're gonna fix that.
That's gonna increase website speed, which is gonna help.
Like that is an outcome that you can build into this, right?
So as we go through the analysis, I'm gonna show you
how we sell outcomes and not services
and how we make it about them and not us.
That's really, really important
to make it about them and not us.
I see the questions coming in, guys, I'll get
to them at the end, feel free to ask them.
But I'm just gonna do a q and a at the end of this session.
Sales is full-time responsibility for someone, right?
This is important. If you're doing founder-led sales,
you're doing sales, you're posting on Instagram,
you're putting out client fires, you're,
you got a million things going on, you can't have this be a
Part-time thing. So
we have Annette, Annette is the,
the SEO support person that we hired to help us.
It's her full-time job, right?
And I support her in any way, shape, or form that I can,
but I can't do it full-time.
I have too much going on. So you
need somebody full-time on this.
Somebody focused on generating revenue for the business.
Because if you're not
and nobody else is, your revenue's gonna struggle.
You know, I think Tony Robbins says it right?
Like we're where attention flows success goes.
I don't know if that's exactly what it's,
but you get the gist of it, right?
Somebody has to be focused on this stuff.
Don't get emotional about deals, right?
Like I said, when we're talking about
maintaining good relationship, don't overthink it.
Don't get too, don't get emotional about it.
The best deal is always the next one.
Always maintain a level head. It's never personal.
It could be, but it's usually not personal.
So don't get emotional about it.
Don't beg, don't plead, don't bother them too much, right?
We'll talk about what that looks like,
but keep in mind that more are coming
and you don't want to just crash out
because you lost a deal.
It's gonna happen. You're gonna lose a lot of deals.
I have lost way more deals than I have won
and that's just a part of the business.
Gotta toughen up a little bit, I guess is the word.
So the role of marketing is to generate interest.
The role of sales is to generate leads.
What that means is that when we do marketing,
and we have a marketing module in here,
marketing is not about, hey, call us right now
for whatever marketing is to build intrigue, engagement,
reach awareness, get people interested in
who you are and what you do.
The role of sales is to turn that interest into a lead.
So what that means, there's a couple
of things that we can do, right?
We talk in our, we have a module all about LinkedIn posting,
but some things that you can do very easily if you are doing
sales, your sales rep is, is doing this,
is is posting on social media.
And I like to say that warm
outbound is better than cold outbound.
So a lot of you out there default to cold outbound
because you don't do marketing, right?
That's a function of sales, not marketing.
I was in, when I was in the sauna yesterday,
this kid was talking about how he gets inbound leads from
doing, uh, from doing cold outbound sales.
And I was like, that is a sentence,
a contradiction in itself.
Like you're doing cold outbound sales
and you're calling them inbound leads.
So you know, that's a function of sales
and that would be the role of the sales rep.
But it's always better to work off of warm list
as opposed to cold list.
So what are warm lists? That means past pitches.
Anyone that you've been in communication with.
That's why having a CRM is so important.
So you can go back through pa once a year, I'll go back
through, I'll have a net pull our database of past contacts.
She'll go through and kind of tag them by stage.
And I'll go through and look at them
and be like, oh, I remember talking to this guy.
You know, I'll send 'em a follow up email. I'll check in.
Just like personal custom one-to-one emails to try
and re-engage interest.
Same thing with your email list.
If you're building an email list, which everyone should be,
you just are just constantly nurturing it with content,
constantly nurturing it, hitting with content.
Eventually people are gonna bite when they see something
and jump back on a call with you.
And then posting on social media again.
You know, so like there's ways that you can use social media
to get people enticed and interested, right?
And that's usually by asking, asking
and soliciting for some sort of post.
We're doing this a lot on Instagram too.
You've probably seen it on Blueprint.
We're doing it more on Weiss.
It's a little bit harder 'cause of the content needed,
but we're finding that Instagram's actually a much better
social network right now than LinkedIn
is for a lot of reasons.
Uh, it's a bit of an old screenshot.
I just didn't update it 'cause we have so many.
But the point is, is that this stuff works, y'all like, uh,
what I'm gonna tell you here is exactly from the playbook of
what I do on a daily basis.
It's what runs our agency
and what allows me to run multiple businesses with,
you know, hundreds of clients and still handle sales myself.
It's, it's really powerful stuff.
So I wanna also quickly talk
before we get into the sales process, just kind
of like some sales housekeeping here, if you will.
This extends a little bit more
to your website and marketing.
I have conversations with my lawyer clients all the time.
Websites are not as much marketing tools as they used to be
because people aren't finding our websites like they used to
through things like Google, right?
Social media has completely changed the discovery business
in terms of how people are discovering businesses.
Even things like Google business profile too, right?
Like a lot of customers don't even end up on your website.
Your website is, is the final touch point with people
before they become a lead essentially, right?
So we're not gonna get into website design function here.
I just wanna focus on the conversion pieces of this.
And for me, you know,
sometimes these old lawyers will be like, Hey look, I want
to your website and couldn't find a phone number.
Like how do I call you?
I'm like, we have a a get started page.
You can book a book a call there
and they're like, I wanna call you.
I'm like, I don't wanna talk to you.
Like if you want to call me, you're not a,
you are not the type of client that I wanna work with.
But like that just tells me everything, right?
So for me, there's no email on our website,
there's no phone number on our website.
I don't want people calling and asking questions.
That's not how this business model works.
It's just not, you don't need a million ways for people
to get in touch with you because all it's gonna do is waste
your time and it's gonna have you chasing down leads
on all these different places.
So a single point of entry is what you need.
Call this the macro conversion page.
I'm gonna show you our
website in a second to go through this.
But like again, it's not a contact page,
it is a get started page.
There should be some sort of offer that drives businesses
to want to talk to you, not contact us Again,
the only thing you're gonna get from contact us is link
builders, resellers, just spam.
Like there's nothing on there there.
We have no forms on our website.
Same thing like forms, just produce spam.
We have no live chat. I have no interest in that.
I have no interest in talking to somebody
who like insists on talking
to us right now when I'm gonna ask them
to spend a hundred thousand dollars.
It's like this isn't a, this isn't a, you need
to talk to me right now thing.
This is a take a time that works for you later this week.
Fill out the form that we're asking for and then we'll talk.
Right? And this is also why marketing is so important
because, and why so many people generate
so many bad leads is 'cause when you force people
or you make it too frictionless,
then you're gonna get people that are just generally not
that interested because they didn't go
through the proper channels
to actually want to work with you.
They're not educated, they're not, they don't know
what they're looking for, right?
Like if you book a call with us, you know exactly what we do
and you know exactly what we're gonna do for you, right?
So I'm gonna show you this.
Just live on our website right now.
These are two different offers that you can use.
We have the traffic projection analysis.
Let's pop open both of these
and then we've got our get started page as well.
So let's start, let's by just looking at our,
our get started page here real quick.
Just log out. 'cause I don't like having this bar on top.
Sorry, I'm I'm particular.
Alright, so what you will notice here, right? Very clear.
This is not a, hey, if you have questions, reach out.
This is work with us with a very specific call to action
for the outcome of what they're gonna get
right from working with us.
And then what they can expect on the call.
We're gonna look at current performance growth
opportunities, areas for
improvement, total addressable market.
So literally the analysis that I'm gonna show you.
Now, what you'll notice here too is there's no form.
This is a Calendly page
and you can only book one week in advance.
I don't want people booking in a month or two.
They're not gonna show up. It's a waste of time.
If they're not ready to have a conversation
this week, come back later.
Not worth my time, right?
This is also part of founder-led sales.
You have to protect your time
and you have to be able to whittle it down.
Like we don't, I don't wanna talk to everyone.
I wanna talk to people that are in market, right?
So all these things, I'm putting up guardrails.
It feels like it's barriers to entry,
but in reality it is barriers to entry.
But it's what I call friction, right?
There's a certain level of friction that you want
to put on this
because we don't want to just talk to, to anybody.
We don't wanna talk to people that are like,
so what do you do?
And what is SEO? Like, no,
get outta here when I'm not talking to you.
Like, go Google that. Like that's not what I'm here for.
That's not what my time is for.
My time is for people that are serious about this.
So you can only book within a week.
It's got tied directly to my calendar.
So after they fill this out here too, it's name, email,
phone number, these are all required law firm's website.
I do this because when we talk about discovery process,
and when I talk about actually if I'm gonna show up
to this call or cancel it, I need this information.
Like if, if you don't put the law firm website here
and they use a Gmail, like I'm not, I don't like,
I, some people do use Gmail.
I get that. Like, you know, like
very powerful lawyers will use Gmail.
'cause I want, I, I sometimes do too
to protect my work email.
But like I need to see the,
the website that's you're attached to.
Because if you don't have website
or you know, a one page Weebly website,
you're just, you're not qualified.
You're just not ready to work to work with us, right?
Or any agency really for that matter that we do.
Then it says, are you actively investing in
marketing for your law firm?
Again, this is required. Again,
these are qualification questions that I know.
Yes, currently working with an agency, managing in house,
no, this helps me understand what their timeline is, right?
If you are working with an agency,
how much time is left on your contract?
90 days or more? I don't know
if I really wanna talk to you right now.
How much are you currently investing? Right?
Gimme an understanding of that.
So we're not, I don't have to ask 'em what their budget is.
I can, they can fill this out right here.
What are you currently doing? They can check all that.
Apply for marketing if we can.
There's an important one, right?
People always ask about like, oh well I wanna put price.
Do I put pricing on my website?
What's included in our service? This is it right here.
Are you willing to at least invest at least $10,000 a month?
And then how did you hear about us? Right?
And also down here, have a video, you know,
and then I've got some frequent last questions.
Also services on here too, right?
So it says our retainer starts at 5,000,
but this one up here says 10,000.
It's it like, it's an easy no-brainer for me now to,
to filter these people out
that just don't meet our level of qualification.
This is really, really, really important.
So another offer that you can use
to traffic rejection analysis.
This is actually like one, one of
the reasons why we built this tool.
So it's just a different offer. We don't run this one
as much because our other page converts really well for us.
But this is the same type of thing.
Just goes through again, outcome. What's your website's?
Organic potential. This is a little bit better
for like advertising
or marketing for maybe that are people like, ah man,
I'm not ready to hire an agency now,
but this is intriguing for me.
It goes through again, what's,
what's included on it goes some
screenshots and results here.
And then again, same thing here with the Calendly embed
and then the FAQs at the bottom, right?
So we add a little bit of social proof here
because we're saying, okay, these people are probably one
step up in the funnel, they're not quite ready
to ask for a proposal yet.
So we're gonna throw a little social
proof on that page as well.
Makes sense? So that is really important.
I know again, this can be a little bit confusing,
but we actually have inside of our marketing module,
all about like the seven page, five page website.
I believe it is. We have page templates for you.
All this stuff is in there.
These links are here for you to look at.
You can obviously go to our website,
please don't book a call.
It's a little bit annoying when people like go
through like, I wanna see what it looked like.
Like you know what it looks like. You
don't need to book a call.
'cause then it kind of, it messes up my data too
and it kind of blocks up my calendar.
So we're just gonna wrap today's session
with a full sales process here.
So I'm gonna jump over here to Miro
and just walk through a little bit more visual diagram
so you guys get a feel for
what does the full sales process look like.
So again, lead comes in and they book a discovery call.
So literally that Calendly
that I just showed you is the discovery call.
So they book that. I'll go in
and I will look at the, the inside of my calendar it,
it pulls through all of the questions that they filled out.
I'll take a quick look at their website,
I'll look at their budget and then I will determine if I
wanna show up for that call or cancel it.
And when I cancel it, I'll send them a nice email saying,
Hey, like this, we're not really good fit.
You know, you know, check out the China club.
So the discovery call is to qualify the lead, build rapport
and energy energy's important.
Get people excited. Get them feeling like you have a,
you have a, you're a good fit for them.
That you have a you a solution to their problems.
It's important too to get verbal interest, right?
Because we don't want to go through the
process without verbal interest.
And you always want to schedule the follow up on this call.
We don't wanna be doing it over email.
Hey, when are you available? Tuesday at 12?
Oh, I just booked like I,
that's like one of my pet peeves in life.
Get it booked on the call. Pull up your calendar,
pull up their calendar, get it
booked for the follow up, right?
That is if they are qualified for this.
So if they're not qualified, you just add them,
leave them next campaign, move it
as like deal not qualified.
And they'll get future emails
and maybe they'll qualify in the future.
So the analysis here, again, this is
what Annette does for me.
If you're doing it yourself, it's gonna take some time.
We have a template for you, don't worry.
But you know, we go through
and we do our scorecard analysis,
traffic projection, put in some solutions.
It's a pretty lengthy document.
We're gonna spend an entire day talking about it.
So then on the analysis call,
this is the most important call, right?
This is an hour, sometimes can go an hour
and a half depending on how many questions that they have.
But we go through, we review the analysis
with them in detail.
We present everything.
I stop for questions, I
make sure that they're on the same page.
I make sure that they're really feeling the
value and the expertise.
And then I'll present the recommendations, AKA,
our service and solutions.
And I'll get a buy-in on price there, right?
So I'll tell them what the price is.
Doesn't have to be exact, but you should
know what it is at this point too.
And then you want to get verbal buy-in there, right?
And then I'll usually ask them like, Hey, do you have time?
We're gonna put together a scope of work.
Do you have 15 minutes on Friday to go through it
with me just to make sure we're on the same page?
The more calls you can have with 'em, the better.
You don't have to have a call.
If they're like, I'm in at that point,
then you don't have to have that call.
You can just send 'em the scope of work.
So again, if they're qualified, leave an active campaign.
If yes, you know, you can send email check-ins in
between calls, let 'em know you're working on it
and you're looking forward to it.
So the proposal is, is very simply just a word document.
You guys already have access to it,
but we'll go through it Again, don't worry.
Everything that's included in terms of your service,
this is really important because you wanna get on the same
page about hey, this is
what you're getting exactly what you're getting.
And then a very simple kind of like timeline matrix
of when they're getting it and then the pricing associated
on a monthly basis, billing terms, all
that stuff goes in there as well.
And then again, this is kind of an optional thing here,
the pitch call, but to go
through in detail the solution in terms of what's included.
A lot of our lawyer clients just kind
of glaze over, so I don't do this too much.
But if they have like an internal marketing team,
it's important because they want
to know the details of what they're getting.
You know, also, this is when we start getting into like the
close of this as well.
I do these on Loom sometimes case by case as well.
I'll run them through. If they gimme like a very excited
verbal yes on the analysis call,
then I'll sometimes just send them a loom running 'em
through it being like, hey, like
let me know when you wanna start.
You always want to ask for an expected decision date.
This is important because this is when you can start getting
more aggressive with the close, right?
Questions about closing is usually around, you know,
how many emails do I send?
How often do I send them?
If you don't have an expected decision date,
then it makes it harder to hold 'em accountable.
So you wanna say, Hey, look at,
can you gimme a decision by next Wednesday?
That's a week from now. Okay, sure.
Now you have something to hold 'em accountable.
Now on af on.
And after that date, you can
follow with them pretty aggressively.
You can text them, you can call them, you can email them
because you've got a verbally agreed upon date
that they can expect the decision by, right?
So that's when the close, you know, starts
to get a little bit more aggressive is
that you've run them through this whole process.
Now you're holding them accountable, right?
That's really what the, the
followup in the close comes down to.
So that's the entire agency sales process.